What happens when you initialize a repository? Why do you need to do it?

When a repository is initialized, a repository is basically created without any initial commits. This repository will h
ave a few files which count as "untracked", and will only count as tracked after the first commit. 
We need to initialize a repository so it creates a .git file and our files can be saved and used for version-control
and program development later on. 


How is the staging area different from the working directory and the repository? What value do you think it offers?

The staging area for me is like a breathing room so that I am able to see what I want to commit and hold back those files
that I have made no changes in from having unnecessary commits. In this way, all my items are controlled and version
changes are pertinent to what I want to do. 


How can you use the staging area to make sure you have one commit per logical change?

by using the staging area as sort of a "buffer zone" when we commit, we can see exactly what goes into each 
commit and therefore commit fast and often. When we commit then, we will be sure to have one commit per
logical change.


What are some situations when branches would be helpful in keeping your history organized? How would branches help?

When we have multiple versions of a file that have the same value in terms of experimentation and usage, we would 
like to have two different versions that both serve a useful function. Branches help by allowing us to edit code
in these versions that can contribute to their respective versions without jeopardizing the state of the other
branches. 


How do the diagrams help you visualize the branch structure?

Using the diagrams, we saw how each branch could separate from the master branch and how changes on the new branch
would be affected through new branch commits, but those commits would not change anything on any of the other branches.


What is the result of merging two branches together? Why do we represent it in the diagram the way we do?

When we merge two branches together, we are able to bring together their differences and create a file that represents
the changes of the collaborators to create a more functional and working product which has been tested by users. The
diagram is represented the way it is because the branches depict what a project should look like when changes go off
in different directions.  


What are the pros and cons of Git’s automatic merging vs. always doing merges manually?

By automatically merging branches, git takes away the users ability to make logical commits to all of its branches.
An automatic commit could make very little logical sense, and therefore have little use in the long run.  By manualy
merging git branches, we can ensure that the branches we merge have the changes we want them to have with the commits
that are useful to the files. 